<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meeting Minutes on 孤筝の温暖小家</title><link>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/tags/meeting-minutes/</link><description>Recent content from 孤筝の温暖小家</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</managingEditor><webMaster>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</webMaster><copyright>Unless otherwise stated, all posts on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license. Please credit the source when reposting!</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 19:46:04 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/tags/meeting-minutes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Summary of the First Semester of Junior Year</title><link>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E5%A4%A7%E4%B8%89%E4%B8%8A%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 19:46:04 +0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author><guid>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E5%A4%A7%E4%B8%89%E4%B8%8A%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93/</guid><description>
<![CDATA[<h1>Summary of the First Semester of Junior Year</h1><p>Author: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
        
          <h2 id="about-final-exams">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#about-final-exams"></a>
About Final Exams
</h2><p>For students, nothing seems more important at the end of a semester than grades. Upholding the <del>fine tradition</del> of last-minute cramming, I studied frantically almost every day during the final two weeks (though I occasionally slacked off—<del>why the hell are there still experiments in week 16?</del>). Thankfully, I didn’t fail any courses, and while my scores weren’t stellar, I’m satisfied (scoring over 70 in aerodynamics after cramming it in a day—no need to elaborate on that skill).</p>
<p>And so, I’ll once again make the empty promise of “next semester, I’ll study properly from the start”—a classic lie, haha.<br>
But seriously, I really should start studying, or how else will I ever earn my Ph.D.?</p>
<h2 id="about-pursuing-a-phd">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#about-pursuing-a-phd"></a>
About Pursuing a Ph.D.
</h2><p>I chose the Qian Xuesen Honors Program’s direct Ph.D. track not for the accelerated 4+3 graduation (though I’m not cut out for that anyway) nor to chase a degree that promises higher salaries or greater “social status.” I believe the person who first translated “Doctor” as “博士” (bóshì, literally “erudite scholar”) intended to emphasize the reputation of being widely learned, not the other trappings.</p>
<p>Though they say “cursing someone into a Ph.D. is a thunderbolt-worthy sin,” and stories of delayed graduations and disillusionment abound, I still want to try my hand at creating something entirely new—something unprecedented. Not for titles, not for academic turf, but simply because it might benefit people and humanity.</p>
<p>As I’ve said before:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>My material demands are modest—just enough to support my family, which seems achievable given my current situation. But I’m dissatisfied with my undergraduate education; four years of study still feel like I haven’t even scratched the surface.</p></blockquote>
<p>To cling to knowledge explored by predecessors decades or centuries ago in this rapidly evolving era? To forsake the frontiers of learning and settle for mere subsistence? I can’t do it.</p>
<p>I may lack talent and perhaps will never achieve much academically, but I refuse to abandon humanity’s courage to explore and innovate. At the very least, I want to stand at the forefront as a witness—to watch generations break through the shackles of matter and mind, to see civilization step out of its gentle cradle and venture into the unknown depths of space.</p>
<p>I can’t give up the thrill of acquiring new knowledge,<br>
because I’ve already touched the sky.</p>
<p>Enough grand talk for today. Deep down, I don’t truly believe I have the power to change anything. Most likely, I’ll end up as an unremarkable academic footnote, barely graduating with a pile of mediocre papers.<br>
But I’ll still try. I’ll still do it. Because the mountain is there.</p>
<h2 id="about-family">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#about-family"></a>
About Family
</h2><p>After such serious topics, let’s lighten the mood.<br>
In August, my mother had surgery at Wuhan Tongji Hospital, and I stayed with her for half a month (<del>though I’m too embarrassed to call it “caretaking”</del>). After her hysterectomy, she rested for two months and regained some energy. But then she went right back to her early-morning-to-late-night work routine. Sigh.<br>
Otherwise, things at home are unchanged, with little to worry about.<br>
I miss the egg-drop sweet soup my grandmother used to make in winter.</p>
<h2 id="about-friends">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#about-friends"></a>
About Friends
</h2><p>Life at school has been uneventful, aside from an electronics competition. My friends are the same as ever, the people I like are doing well, and everyone’s living their own lives.<br>
<strong>“At the ends of the earth, half my dear friends are scattered.”</strong></p>
<h2 id="about-my-trip-to-hungary">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#about-my-trip-to-hungary"></a>
About My Trip to Hungary
</h2><p>I signed up for the winter break exchange program at Óbuda University organized by the School of Space Science. I’ve been here for two weeks and am about to head back.<br>
Learned some useless AI applications—nothing to do with my future studies, and I didn’t expect to acquire any “dragon-slaying skills” anyway.</p>
<p>The first few days of “white people food” were awful; I couldn’t fathom how locals survive on this. But the meals gradually improved. I tried authentic Hungarian goulash (a beef stew with potatoes, carrots, etc.) at a local spot, and it was delicious. The pork knuckle here is also incredible—huge portions and tasty (<del>though why is it translated as “toe joint”?</del>).</p>
<p>The steak, though? Forget it—served rare by default, tough to cut and chew. The ubiquitous dry bread is inedible, and the salads might as well be rocks.</p>
<p>Another standout was the bathrooms. Every single one I’ve seen here is spotless, with attendants, stocked toilet paper, soap, hand dryers, and paper towels (OMG). The dorm bathrooms even have bidet sprayers and bleach-soaked toilet brushes. All faucets provide 24/7 hot and cold water, and the heating is so intense that indoors often feels like a sauna.</p>
<p>The only downside? Almost no public restrooms, and some places charge for toilet access.</p>
<p>Sigh. Developed countries have money to burn on resources. It breaks my heart to think of villagers in northern China who can’t afford heating in winter or southerners who can’t run AC in summer.<br>
Too many people in this world suffer. Comrades, we must keep striving.</p>
<p>I bought some authentic souvenirs to bring back, but I won’t spoil the surprise for friends who might read this.</p>
<h2 id="closing-thoughts">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#closing-thoughts"></a>
Closing Thoughts
</h2><p>Flying home tomorrow for the New Year, and I’m brimming with nostalgia.<br>
The remaining half of winter break <em>should</em> be spent studying <em>Principles of Communications</em> (maybe it will, maybe it won’t).<br>
Wishing you a happy New Year, peace and prosperity in the years to come.</p>
<p>Jan 24, 2025</p>

        
        <hr><p>Published on 2025-01-28 at <a href='https://guzhengsvt.cn/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>, last modified on 2025-01-28</p><p>Unless otherwise stated, all posts on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license. Please credit the source when reposting!</p>]]></description><category>Thoughts</category></item><item><title>Because spring once came</title><link>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/poetry/%E5%9B%A0%E4%B8%BA%E6%98%A5%E5%A4%A9%E6%9D%A5%E8%BF%87/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:07:40 +0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author><guid>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/poetry/%E5%9B%A0%E4%B8%BA%E6%98%A5%E5%A4%A9%E6%9D%A5%E8%BF%87/</guid><description>
<![CDATA[<h1>Because spring once came</h1><p>Author: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
        
          <h3 id="this-poem-is-dedicated-to-the-polaris-in-my-life">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#this-poem-is-dedicated-to-the-polaris-in-my-life"></a>
——This poem is dedicated to the Polaris in my life
</h3><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/11/1787644976.jpg" alt="IMG_4884.jpg"></p>
<p><strong>A lovely traveler passed through a landscape unseen by others, bringing with her exotic warm breezes that swept across parched fields, rustled through treetops, and rippled the lake into shimmering waves.<br>
The fruit trees, enchanted by this beauty, hurriedly blossomed and bore fruit; birds in the forest scoured for the few remaining flowering branches, weaving them into a crown for her.<br>
Strolling through the falling petals, the traveler, unable to refuse such generosity, plucked a few crimson fruits; feeling shy about taking without giving, she emptied her pockets of all the flower seeds she carried, scattering them over every cracked patch of earth.<br>
Only the field remained barren, its heart filled with shyness and guilt—what could it possibly offer this delightful maiden?<br>
Summoning all its strength, it urged the seeds to grow swiftly, hoping she might witness the blossoms before she left.<br>
But the traveler was never meant to stay—the scenery was beautiful, the trees and birds most attentive, yet this was no place to call home.<br>
She departed, leaving behind wistful fruit trees, birds, and the field.<br>
The field’s flowers never reached her hands, though perhaps the next traveler would find a garden in full bloom.<br>
Yet none grieved,<br>
for spring had come.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Winter gave way to spring, autumn yielded to winter.<br>
Fruits became saplings, fledglings took their first flights; tree rings thickened, and summer rains polished wings to a gleam.<br>
In the garden the field had tenderly nurtured, the last chrysanthemum outlived its season, bare stems swaying in the cold wind.<br>
No longer desolate, the land had seen the traveler’s seeds sprout through the seasons, each flower blooming in its turn as promised—drinking dawn’s dew, basking in morning sun, dancing in the breeze, resting under moonlight.<br>
In spring, the field wove a crown of gardenias and hawthorn blossoms, white as the traveler’s dress.<br>
In summer, it fashioned a basket of crape myrtle and hibiscus, though the hibiscus wilted by dusk, much like her fleeting visit.<br>
In autumn, it dreamed of a bed sweet with osmanthus and aster, but the wind carried the fragrance away, indifferent to its longing.<br>
The flowers, embracing their purpose, reveled in their brief lives, preparing in the soil for journeys yet to come.<br>
The traveler never returned, unaware that her casually scattered seeds had grown into a garden, and the field never had its chance to offer its finest tribute.<br>
Winter gave way to spring, autumn yielded to winter.<br>
The field longed for snow, a warm blanket for the seeds below. Should the traveler ever revisit this hidden paradise, the garden would be worthy of her.<br>
In the drizzle of early winter, it drifted into sleep, dreaming of October’s last dandelions riding the wind, chasing the blush on her cheeks.<br>
“Aren’t you afraid the seeds won’t survive the cold?” asked the trees and birds, as the field lay bare once more.<br>
“It’s alright. I’ve seen spring.”<br>
For spring had come.</strong></p>
        
        <hr><p>Published on 2024-11-13 at <a href='https://guzhengsvt.cn/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>, last modified on 2024-11-13</p><p>Unless otherwise stated, all posts on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license. Please credit the source when reposting!</p>]]></description><category>Poetry</category></item><item><title>Send One Each Day</title><link>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E6%97%A5%E5%AF%84%E5%85%B6%E4%B8%80/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:02:00 +0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author><guid>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E6%97%A5%E5%AF%84%E5%85%B6%E4%B8%80/</guid><description>
<![CDATA[<h1>Send One Each Day</h1><p>Author: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
        
          <p>The last update was a month ago—not because I was particularly busy (though there were indeed hectic moments). It’s just that life is unpredictable, and I found myself with little motivation to write.</p>
<h2 id="a-thousand-miles-away-the-northern-wind-blows-against-my-clothes">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#a-thousand-miles-away-the-northern-wind-blows-against-my-clothes"></a>
A Thousand Miles Away, the Northern Wind Blows Against My Clothes
</h2><p>Shortly after finishing my final exams, I rushed to Tongji Hospital to take care of my mother, just as she had come to care for me when I was in fifth grade.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/08/3979775032.jpg" alt="IMG_0162.JPG"></p>
<p>Taken at Building No. 2 of Tongji Hospital’s inpatient department. The rooftop was scorching and windy, so clothes had to be tied down tightly with ropes.</p>
<p>After her discharge, I stayed home for over ten days, doing nothing but idling away my time on Chao and <em>Ace Attorney</em>.</p>
<p>Eating and drinking at home—blending watermelon into juice and chilling it was absolutely delicious, and banana with milk wasn’t bad either.</p>
<h2 id="off-to-changan-three-thousand-miles-from-home">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#off-to-changan-three-thousand-miles-from-home"></a>
Off to Chang’an, Three Thousand Miles from Home
</h2><p>Once she could take care of herself again, I boarded a train to Chang’an (Xi’an).</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/08/4064831348.jpg" alt="IMG_0330.JPG"></p>
<p>I’ve never been one to cling to home, always yearning to wander far and wide, never looking back. They’ve grown old and can’t keep up with me anymore. My father, like all parents whose children are leaving home, threw a bit of a tantrum, while my mother simply watched from afar.</p>
<p>Their son has his own life now, speaking words that sound fresh and unfamiliar to them. The more sensible I become, the more distant I seem. Will we ever miss those days when I’d throw tantrums for dumplings or remote-controlled cars? Back then, they were still young, and so was I.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To stay or leave, neither holds meaning,<br>
The lingering clouds make it hard to rest.<br>
The setting sun seals the lonely city,<br>
No plan to return to Yanran Peak.<br>
Only this melody can soothe a broken heart.</p>
<p>— <em>&ldquo;Memories of Chang’an&rdquo;</em></p></blockquote>
<h2 id="this-melody-once-played-will-leave-its-mark">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#this-melody-once-played-will-leave-its-mark"></a>
This Melody, Once Played, Will Leave Its Mark
</h2><p>The graduate dormitories at school have been completed, while several shops in the main building have closed (the hardest to swallow was Mixue Ice Cream &amp; Tea).</p>
<p>On the way here, I bought portraits of Chairman Mao and the five great mentors. I pasted a young Mao on my wardrobe door as a constant reminder (though it’s never been of much use, haha).</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/08/3618386613.jpg" alt="IMG_0405.JPG"></p>
<p>Anime + communism—I must be some kind of divine being. On the left is fantasy, on the right is dreams, and beneath my feet is my mission.</p>
<p>A slight surprise was receiving the certificate and ring from UNICEF.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/08/2489695285.jpg" alt="IMG_0342 (1).JPG"></p>
<p>A classmate told me this counts as an international award and could boost my comprehensive evaluation score (laughs). What good is that for someone who’s failed courses?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If only I could shelter all the scholars under a thousand roofs,<br>
Unshaken by wind or rain, steadfast as a mountain!</p></blockquote>
<p>The certificate arrived on July 28, the <strong>48th anniversary of the Tangshan Earthquake</strong>.</p>
<p>I have a dream—that one day, everyone will have a sturdy home to live in.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/08/1524464415.jpg" alt="A Tower That Will Never Collapse.jpg"></p>
<p>Xi’an’s summer is as hot as back home, if not more stifling, leaving me drenched in sweat at the slightest movement.</p>
<p>Pulled an all-nighter during the four-day, three-night electronics competition, but I’m used to it by now.</p>
<p>For Project F, I built a magnetic levitation toy. Since magnets weren’t allowed for the base, I brute-forced it with power—eight small coils and one large one, hand-wound several times. I gave it my all.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/08/4263497725.jpg" alt="IMG_0386 (1).JPG"></p>
<p>During the final evaluation, it levitated at 1.5 cm, earning 35 points.</p>
<p>I’m satisfied. Though the official results aren’t out yet, I’ve already popped the champagne.</p>
<p>Aim for silver, reach for gold (i.e., secure a provincial second prize and aim for first).</p>
<p>At least I’ve held myself accountable.</p>
<h2 id="time-flows-like-ink-washing-the-sky-blue">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#time-flows-like-ink-washing-the-sky-blue"></a>
Time Flows Like Ink, Washing the Sky Blue
</h2><p>After the evaluation today, I loitered in EII-210 for the air conditioning (damn dorm maintenance cutting the power). Scrolled through Chao and watched videos until 6 p.m.</p>
<p>With nothing better to do, I browsed online shops and bought a bunch of snacks, thinking that if they tasted good, I might share them with family and friends.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/08/2871930292.png" alt="IMG_0403 (1).PNG"></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/08/3701669522.png" alt="IMG_0404.PNG"></p>
<p>Got back and accomplished nothing again, booted up <em>Battlefield 1</em> until 11 p.m. Ruined, kid.</p>
<p>Wasted enough time. A month ago, I said I’d publish notes on electromagnetic fields and waves—now the progress is infinitely close to zero.</p>
<p>Starting tomorrow, I’ll study hard and get back on track.</p>
<p>Wait, no—today, since it’s already past midnight (o(<em>￣▽￣</em>)ブ).</p>
<p>Hope to get some real work done before <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em> comes out.</p>
<p>While writing, I recalled the taste of that chilled, freshly blended watermelon juice from home. Now I’m hungry.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I’ve always been glad to wander the world,<br>
But Chang’an has no flavor quite like this.</p></blockquote>
<p>The night is deep, and words can’t capture all I feel.</p>
<p>Only this melody can make me forget the world.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/08/3364523607.png" alt="fuguang.png"></p>
<p>Good night.</p>

        
        <hr><p>Published on 2024-08-04 at <a href='https://guzhengsvt.cn/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>, last modified on 2024-08-04</p><p>Unless otherwise stated, all posts on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license. Please credit the source when reposting!</p>]]></description><category>Thoughts</category></item><item><title>Newly assembled computer</title><link>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E6%96%B0%E8%A3%85%E7%94%B5%E8%84%91/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 16:30:10 +0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author><guid>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E6%96%B0%E8%A3%85%E7%94%B5%E8%84%91/</guid><description>
<![CDATA[<h1>Newly assembled computer</h1><p>Author: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
        
          <p>This year, I treated myself to a new desktop PC for my birthday</p>
<p>. My old setup from four years ago—a 9700KF paired with a 1660S—was no longer cutting it, and the 1080P 60Hz monitor had become underwhelming.</p>
<p>After selling the old PC and monitor, plus dipping into my savings, I barely managed to scrape together enough for the upgrade.</p>
<h3 id="spec-list">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#spec-list"></a>
Spec List
</h3><ul>
<li><strong>CPU</strong>: 12400F (loose chip)</li>
<li><strong>Motherboard</strong>: ASUS 610M-A D4</li>
<li><strong>Cooler</strong>: Thermalright AX120 R SE White</li>
<li><strong>GPU</strong>: Yeston RX 7700XT Sakura Blossom Bride</li>
<li><strong>RAM</strong>: Klevv 16GB×2 DDR4 3600MHz</li>
<li><strong>SSD</strong>: Fanxiang 1TB S500PRO</li>
<li><strong>PSU</strong>: MSI MAG A650BNL Bronze</li>
<li><strong>Case</strong>: Aigo Xiao Lan White Panoramic (no center pillar)</li>
<li><strong>Fans</strong>: 4× Aurora regular fans + 3× reverse fans</li>
<li><strong>Monitor</strong>: Koorui X41Q 23.8-inch 2K 180Hz</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="assembly">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#assembly"></a>
Assembly
</h3><p>The build wasn’t too difficult overall—just watched a Hardware Tea Talk video and got to work.</p>
  
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">  
  <iframe   
    src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=818609247&bvid=BV1BG4y137mG&cid=918273402&p=1"  
    style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;"   
    frameborder="0"   
    allowfullscreen="true">  
  </iframe>  
</div>  


<p>The main challenges were installing the fans, GPU brace, and case wiring:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Fans</strong>: The included self-tapping screws required high torque to thread. Regular fans were easier to mount from the outside, but the reverse fan between the PSU and GPU had undersized screw holes—luckily, the case’s longer screws worked.</li>
<li><strong>Cable Management Nightmare</strong>: All seven fans had RGB, so their 4-pin power cables had to be daisy-chained to the motherboard (unsure if it could handle the load). The 5V 3-pin ARGB cables also needed chaining, including one from the GPU’s ARGB strip. The resulting spaghetti was impossible to tidy with zip ties. The non-modular MSI PSU had stiff cables, and the cramped case (small size + bulky air cooler + chonky GPU) made front-panel routing a pain.</li>
<li><strong>GPU Woes</strong>: While not excessively long, the GPU was absurdly thick—less than a centimeter of clearance from the reverse fan. To fit the brace, I had to tear off its bottom cushion foam, likely voiding the case warranty. Oh, and three cables are now pinned under the GPU… fingers crossed.</li>
<li><strong>Case Wiring</strong>: Connecting the front-panel headers wasn’t hard, but I misaligned them multiple times, leading to frantic troubleshooting when it wouldn’t POST.</li>
<li><strong>Gave Up on Cable Management</strong>: Closed the back panel—out of sight, out of mind.</li>
</ol>
<p>Behold the final product (it’s <em>very</em> aesthetically pleasing, like, 9.5/10):<br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/04/621105844.jpg" alt="Front View"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/04/3154335624.jpg" alt="Side View"></p>
<p>I chose the 7700XT over the 4060Ti because:</p>
<ul>
<li>No plans for AI workloads anytime soon. Even if I did, the 4060Ti’s performance would be inadequate.</li>
<li>The 4060Ti 16GB is currently overpriced (~¥4000) due to a minor crypto-mining surge.</li>
</ul>
<p>So, I’ll stick to gaming with this beast (and admire the Sakura Blossom Bride GPU’s beauty—yes, it <em>actually</em> smells nice, hehe).</p>
<p>P.S. The Sakura Blossom Bride card is <em>gorgeous</em>&hellip; and it genuinely has a fragrance. Hehehe.</p>
        
        <hr><p>Published on 2024-04-29 at <a href='https://guzhengsvt.cn/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>, last modified on 2024-04-29</p><p>Unless otherwise stated, all posts on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license. Please credit the source when reposting!</p>]]></description><category>Thoughts</category></item><item><title>The Traveler and the Flower</title><link>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/poetry/%E6%97%85%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8E%E8%8A%B1%E5%84%BF/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 20:13:15 +0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author><guid>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/poetry/%E6%97%85%E4%BA%BA%E4%B8%8E%E8%8A%B1%E5%84%BF/</guid><description>
<![CDATA[<h1>The Traveler and the Flower</h1><p>Author: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
        
          <p>A lovely traveler passed by a landscape that no one appreciated. She brought with her an exotic warm breeze that swept across the parched fields, brushed the treetops, and rippled the lake into a shimmering glow.</p>
<p>The fruit trees, utterly enchanted by this beauty, hurriedly blossomed and bore fruit; the birds in the forest scoured the land for the few remaining flowering branches, weaving them into a wreath to crown her head.</p>
<p>Strolling through the flurry of falling petals, the traveler, unable to refuse such generosity, plucked a few crimson fruits. Feeling guilty for taking without giving, she emptied her pockets of all the flower seeds she carried and scattered them across every cracked patch of earth.</p>
<p>Only the barren field felt shy and ashamed—what could it offer to this lovely maiden?</p>
<p>Summoning all its strength, the field urged the seeds to grow as fast as they could, hoping she might see the flowers in full bloom before she left.</p>
<p>But the traveler was never meant to stay long—the scenery here was truly beautiful, the trees and birds most attentive, yet this was not a place to call home.</p>
<p>When the traveler departed, the fruit trees, the birds, and the field all felt a pang of longing.</p>
<p>The field’s flowers never reached her hands, but perhaps the next traveler would see a splendid garden in their place.</p>
<p><strong>Yet no one grieved over this,</strong></p>
<p><strong>for spring had once visited.</strong></p>

        
        <hr><p>Published on 2023-12-18 at <a href='https://guzhengsvt.cn/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>, last modified on 2023-12-18</p><p>Unless otherwise stated, all posts on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license. Please credit the source when reposting!</p>]]></description><category>Poetry</category></item><item><title>New Domain</title><link>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E6%96%B0%E5%A2%9E%E5%9F%9F%E5%90%8D/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 18:59:05 +0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author><guid>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E6%96%B0%E5%A2%9E%E5%9F%9F%E5%90%8D/</guid><description>
<![CDATA[<h1>New Domain</h1><p>Author: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
        
          <p>I purchased a new domain, guzhengsvt.cn, on Alibaba Cloud.</p>
<p>(Used a coupon for 29￥ the first year, with a renewal fee of 39￥ annually).</p>
<p>Originally, I intended to use it temporarily for WeChat Mini Program development, but it wasn&rsquo;t needed, so I ended up pointing it to my blog instead.</p>
<p>Since multi-domain SSL certificates are too expensive, I used the <a href="https://www.mfpad.com/">MiFa</a> domain redirection service to redirect guzhengsvt.cn to guzhengsvt.top.</p>
<p>I already had an Alibaba Cloud-signed SSL certificate for the .top domain, expiring in August 2024. However, on November 14 this year, Alibaba Cloud updated its free SSL certificate policy—now allowing only single-domain SSL certificates with a maximum validity of 3 months per application. This means I’d have to frequently renew the certificate for the newly purchased .cn domain (though I don’t really need it right now anyway).</p>
<p>I reviewed the steps for domain resolution and SSL certificate application/configuration, and I must thank <a href="https://www.vpsor.cn/">VPSor</a> for how easy their SSL certificate setup is.<br>
<del>I was going to praise Alibaba Cloud’s SSL certificate service too, but&hellip; well, emmm.</del></p>
        
        <hr><p>Published on 2023-11-25 at <a href='https://guzhengsvt.cn/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>, last modified on 2023-11-25</p><p>Unless otherwise stated, all posts on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license. Please credit the source when reposting!</p>]]></description><category>Thoughts</category></item><item><title>Standards for Friendship (Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence)</title><link>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E4%BA%A4%E5%8F%8B%E6%A0%87%E5%87%86%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B3%E5%85%B1%E5%A4%84%E4%BA%94%E9%A1%B9%E5%8E%9F%E5%88%99/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 11:08:56 +0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author><guid>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/%E4%BA%A4%E5%8F%8B%E6%A0%87%E5%87%86%E5%92%8C%E5%B9%B3%E5%85%B1%E5%A4%84%E4%BA%94%E9%A1%B9%E5%8E%9F%E5%88%99/</guid><description>
<![CDATA[<h1>Standards for Friendship (Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence)</h1><p>Author: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
        
          <p>Recently expanded my social circle, so I took some time to draft the <strong>Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence</strong> as a long-term standard for friendships.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>I am, by general and universal standards, a human male—a staunch non-transgender individual and heterosexual, non-vegetarian, and not an extreme environmentalist. I am an atheist, a firm communist, and a patriot.<br>
I fully understand and respect minority groups, including ethnic minorities and the LGBTQ+ community.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I am a long-time user of platforms like Bilibili, AcFun, Zhihu, Quora, Tieba, Xiao Hei He, NGA, A Island, Ruisi, Twitter, Facebook, Pixiv, and various other communities and forums. I am well-versed in internet memes, clapbacks, sharp critiques, and insider jargon. I have the emotional intelligence and discernment to distinguish sincerity from sarcasm and the resilience to handle all forms of insults.<br>
That said, I pledge not to be the first to use offensive language and to maintain full respect for individuals as &ldquo;people.&rdquo; In short, I neither wish to insult others nor fear being insulted.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I have a superficial understanding of:</p>
<ul>
<li>Pan-ACGN culture (anime, animated films, 2D online games, <em>Touhou Project</em>, galgames, ACG music, illustrations, manga, etc.),</li>
<li>Music (classical, traditional Chinese, instrumental, folk, Western, Japanese, etc.),</li>
<li>Literature (sci-fi novels, essays, select &ldquo;classic&rdquo; novels, ancient Chinese poetry and prose, modern Chinese poetry, and some philosophical and social science works).<br>
I have no interest in short videos, pop culture, trending national games, fan circles, domestic entertainment, or topics related to attractive celebrities, though I respect these fully. Please refrain from excessively recommending such content to me.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Under normal circumstances, my posting frequency on QQ Space and WeChat Moments does not exceed one post per day. If this bothers you, feel free to mute me—if you don’t know how, contact me for assistance.<br>
If you prefer long-form content, follow my personal blog: <a href="https://guzhengsvt.cn/">https://guzhengsvt.cn/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>General questions and psychological consultations are free of charge, though I don’t guarantee fixed response times. For consultations you wish to archive, please email me (<a href="mailto:lvbowen040427@163.com">lvbowen040427@163.com</a>).<br>
I promise strict confidentiality of personal privacy and strive to provide fair, comprehensive advice and evaluations—though I cannot guarantee optimal outcomes. Consequences are at your own discretion.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Final interpretation rights belong to me.</p>
</li>
</ol>

        
        <hr><p>Published on 2023-05-14 at <a href='https://guzhengsvt.cn/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>, last modified on 2023-05-14</p><p>Unless otherwise stated, all posts on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license. Please credit the source when reposting!</p>]]></description><category>Thoughts</category></item><item><title>July 14, 2022 - Reborn</title><link>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 13:14:52 +0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author><guid>https://guzhengsvt.cn/en/post/thoughts/2022/</guid><description>
<![CDATA[<h1>July 14, 2022 - Reborn</h1><p>Author: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
        
          <p>On this day, I was truly reborn.</p>

        
        <hr><p>Published on 2022-07-14 at <a href='https://guzhengsvt.cn/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>, last modified on 2022-07-14</p><p>Unless otherwise stated, all posts on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license. Please credit the source when reposting!</p>]]></description><category>Thoughts</category></item></channel></rss>