<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel><title>Poetry on 孤筝の温暖小家</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/poetry/</link>
    <description>Recent content from 孤筝の温暖小家</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</webMaster>
    
    <copyright>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</copyright>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:16:35 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/poetry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss&#43;xml" />
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The East is Red</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E4%B8%9C%E6%96%B9%E7%BA%A2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:16:35 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E4%B8%9C%E6%96%B9%E7%BA%A2/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>The East is Red</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <h3 id="the-east-is-red">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#the-east-is-red"></a>
The East is Red
</h3><p><strong>Midstream strokes resound through the skies, as night by night the river’s roar doth rise.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Not youth alone beholds the morning sun—ten thousand miles of land in crimson run.</strong></p>
<p>Dec. 26, 2024<br>
Xi’an</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/12/1795319606.jpeg" alt="IMG_0434.jpeg"></p>

        <hr><p>本文 2024-12-26 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2024-12-26</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Poetry</category>
      
    </item>
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Because spring once came</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E5%9B%A0%E4%B8%BA%E6%98%A5%E5%A4%A9%E6%9D%A5%E8%BF%87/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:07:40 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E5%9B%A0%E4%B8%BA%E6%98%A5%E5%A4%A9%E6%9D%A5%E8%BF%87/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>Because spring once came</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <h3 id="this-poem-is-dedicated-to-the-polaris-in-my-life">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#this-poem-is-dedicated-to-the-polaris-in-my-life"></a>
——This poem is dedicated to the Polaris in my life
</h3><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/11/1787644976.jpg" alt="IMG_4884.jpg"></p>
<p><strong>A lovely traveler passed through a landscape unseen by others, bringing with her exotic warm breezes that swept across parched fields, rustled through treetops, and rippled the lake into shimmering waves.<br>
The fruit trees, enchanted by this beauty, hurriedly blossomed and bore fruit; birds in the forest scoured for the few remaining flowering branches, weaving them into a crown for her.<br>
Strolling through the falling petals, the traveler, unable to refuse such generosity, plucked a few crimson fruits; feeling shy about taking without giving, she emptied her pockets of all the flower seeds she carried, scattering them over every cracked patch of earth.<br>
Only the field remained barren, its heart filled with shyness and guilt—what could it possibly offer this delightful maiden?<br>
Summoning all its strength, it urged the seeds to grow swiftly, hoping she might witness the blossoms before she left.<br>
But the traveler was never meant to stay—the scenery was beautiful, the trees and birds most attentive, yet this was no place to call home.<br>
She departed, leaving behind wistful fruit trees, birds, and the field.<br>
The field’s flowers never reached her hands, though perhaps the next traveler would find a garden in full bloom.<br>
Yet none grieved,<br>
for spring had come.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Winter gave way to spring, autumn yielded to winter.<br>
Fruits became saplings, fledglings took their first flights; tree rings thickened, and summer rains polished wings to a gleam.<br>
In the garden the field had tenderly nurtured, the last chrysanthemum outlived its season, bare stems swaying in the cold wind.<br>
No longer desolate, the land had seen the traveler’s seeds sprout through the seasons, each flower blooming in its turn as promised—drinking dawn’s dew, basking in morning sun, dancing in the breeze, resting under moonlight.<br>
In spring, the field wove a crown of gardenias and hawthorn blossoms, white as the traveler’s dress.<br>
In summer, it fashioned a basket of crape myrtle and hibiscus, though the hibiscus wilted by dusk, much like her fleeting visit.<br>
In autumn, it dreamed of a bed sweet with osmanthus and aster, but the wind carried the fragrance away, indifferent to its longing.<br>
The flowers, embracing their purpose, reveled in their brief lives, preparing in the soil for journeys yet to come.<br>
The traveler never returned, unaware that her casually scattered seeds had grown into a garden, and the field never had its chance to offer its finest tribute.<br>
Winter gave way to spring, autumn yielded to winter.<br>
The field longed for snow, a warm blanket for the seeds below. Should the traveler ever revisit this hidden paradise, the garden would be worthy of her.<br>
In the drizzle of early winter, it drifted into sleep, dreaming of October’s last dandelions riding the wind, chasing the blush on her cheeks.<br>
“Aren’t you afraid the seeds won’t survive the cold?” asked the trees and birds, as the field lay bare once more.<br>
“It’s alright. I’ve seen spring.”<br>
For spring had come.</strong></p>
        <hr><p>本文 2024-11-13 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2024-11-13</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Poetry</category>
      
    </item>
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Poems from a Journey to Southern Shanxi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E6%99%8B%E5%8D%97%E8%A1%8C%E4%BA%94%E9%A6%96/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 15:47:32 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E6%99%8B%E5%8D%97%E8%A1%8C%E4%BA%94%E9%A6%96/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>Five Poems from a Journey to Southern Shanxi</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <h2 id="preface">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#preface"></a>
Preface
</h2><p>During the National Day holiday, I traveled through Shanxi with <em>Black Myth: Wukong</em>, visiting three cities in southern Shanxi—Jincheng, Linfen, and Yuncheng—and composed five poems to briefly document the journey.</p>
<h2 id="southern-shanxi-journey--part-1">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#southern-shanxi-journey--part-1"></a>
Southern Shanxi Journey · Part 1
</h2><p><strong>The door hides broken statues, the eaves bear golden chimes.<br>
Dabs of emerald dye the tangled woods, splashes of ink unfold jade skirts.<br>
Fresh branches climb rotten wood, the old lead the young.<br>
Lin Huiyin would weep—can a thousand years leave blank space?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lone Zither<br>
October 2, 2024<br>
Jade Emperor Temple, Fucheng Guan Yu Temple, Qinglian Temple, Jincheng</strong></p>
<p>At the Jade Emperor Temple, flash photography is banned in the Hall of Twenty-Eight Constellations, and the statues are hidden behind iron railings, their paint peeling, some even headless or limbless—a regrettable sight.<br>
The statues at Fucheng Guan Yu Temple are mostly modern recreations, crudely made and unappetizing. The architecture, however, is worth a look.<br>
Qinglian Temple sits high on a distant mountain, with breathtaking scenery along the way. In autumn, the mountains are lush, the waters clear, dotted with broad red and yellow leaves under a cloudless sky—a land of splendor.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/4175125506.jpg" alt="IMG_0808 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/2744194162.jpg" alt="IMG_0836 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/4200527731.jpg" alt="IMG_1026 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/126764360.jpg" alt="IMG_0915 (1).JPG"></p>
<h2 id="southern-shanxi-journey--part-2">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#southern-shanxi-journey--part-2"></a>
Southern Shanxi Journey · Part 2
</h2><p><strong>Weary, the Green Emperor has yet to take his post, morning mist rushes to break the dawn’s chill.<br>
Just crossed seas of people to glimpse the Buddha’s face, now climb forested clouds to visit the temple.<br>
Nine golden bodies, nine lotuses, three gates, three altars.<br>
Before the scaled sunset gathers dusk, my light steed has leaped over layered peaks.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lone Zither<br>
October 3, 2024<br>
Kaihua Temple, Iron Buddha Temple, Dinglin Temple, Jincheng</strong></p>
<p>Early in the morning, I took the bus to Gaoping, first visiting Kaihua Temple before returning to Iron Buddha Temple. The latter, newly reopened, was packed, tucked deep in a small village courtyard. After queuing for over an hour, I glimpsed the Buddha’s face for just two minutes. Fortunately, I met a family of three in line—open-minded parents unbothered by anime and games. (Their twin-tailed daughter was adorable, by the way.)<br>
Dinglin Temple’s lotus caisson ceiling had also recently reopened, and I was lucky to see it—truly magnificent.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/438599092.jpg" alt="IMG_0998 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/1955933777.jpg" alt="IMG_1044 (1).JPG"></p>
<h2 id="southern-shanxi-journey--part-3">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#southern-shanxi-journey--part-3"></a>
Southern Shanxi Journey · Part 3
</h2><h3 id="prelude-to-water-melody">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#prelude-to-water-melody"></a>
Prelude to Water Melody
</h3><p><strong>The Buddha feasts on incense offerings, stone tablets drown in dust.<br>
I ask the hills beneath his seat: do sutras reach the divine?<br>
Shorn locks renounce desire, abstinence purges the halls,<br>
smiles mask wrath. They know the laws of five aggregates,<br>
yet fail to grasp the body of ignorance.<br>
False cymbals, temple repairs, deceiving the credulous.<br>
Promises of merit mimic the Tathagata’s great vehicle.<br>
Bribes buy devotion, virtue lacks faith—<br>
the Eight Precepts mislead the sangha.<br>
The chime-keeper chants wealth, the false Buddha saves worldly monks.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lone Zither<br>
October 4, 2024<br>
Little Western Heaven, Linfen</strong></p>
<p><strong>Eight Precepts</strong>:</p>
<ol>
<li>No killing.</li>
<li>No stealing.</li>
<li>No sexual misconduct.</li>
<li>No lying.</li>
<li>No intoxication.</li>
<li>No adornments.</li>
<li>No high or broad beds.</li>
<li>No eating after noon.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Yellow Brow’s Counter</strong>:<br>
No killing? Hatred never ends.<br>
No stealing? Why distinguish strong from weak?<br>
No lust? All sentience is sin.<br>
No lies? Dreams, bubbles, shadows, void.<br>
No wine? Sorrow ebbs and flows.<br>
No pleasure? Beauty fades in a blink.<br>
No sloth? Suffering binds without release.<br>
No indulgence? All acts are joyless.</p>
<p>The lower temple of Little Western Heaven was unremarkable, filled with devotees praying for wealth and sons. A nun (?) sat nearby striking a chime, chanting promises of billions in daily earnings—utterly cynical.<br>
The upper temple’s Mahavira Hall boasts astonishing hanging sculptures, grand in scale. Sadly, the crowds left little time for close inspection. I arrived too late to receive Shanxi’s official commemorative postcard—a slight regret.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/837638753.jpg" alt="IMG_1144 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/377169443.jpg" alt="IMG_1929 (1).JPG"></p>
<h2 id="southern-shanxi-journey--part-4">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#southern-shanxi-journey--part-4"></a>
Southern Shanxi Journey · Part 4
</h2><p><strong>An ancient temple guards Pingyang, three quakes veil the Buddha’s light.<br>
The towering glazed pagoda, the ethereal Arhat Hall.<br>
Scriptures sought through merit, rain prayed for by kings.<br>
A canon passed to the East, the golden age of Tang began.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lone Zither<br>
October 6, 2024<br>
Guang Sheng Temple, Linfen</strong></p>
<p>Guang Sheng Temple in Hongtong County features a Rain God Temple in its lower complex, its walls covered in murals, though poorly preserved. The dim light inside made details hard to discern. Side rooms displayed official scanned reproductions—vivid and lifelike, truly masterful.<br>
The upper temple’s Flying Rainbow Pagoda is clad in glazed tiles, though only the first floor is open, with little to see inside.<br>
The rear courtyard’s Tianzhongtian Hall houses three colossal Buddhas, over ten feet tall, their elegant forms a marvel.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/2152415040.jpg" alt="IMG_1956 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/270551755.jpg" alt="IMG_1985 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/4038570737.jpg" alt="IMG_2006 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/193997803.jpg" alt="IMG_2037 (2).JPG"></p>
<h2 id="southern-shanxi-journey--part-5">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#southern-shanxi-journey--part-5"></a>
Southern Shanxi Journey · Part 5
</h2><h3 id="encountering-wei-taoran-at-stork-tower">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#encountering-wei-taoran-at-stork-tower"></a>
Encountering Wei Taoran at Stork Tower
</h3><p><strong>No immortal of wine was I born,<br>
inking brows, grinding words.<br>
At Stork Tower, I duel Wang Zhihuan,<br>
below Taihang, I ponder the Chairman.<br>
You roam the world a free spirit,<br>
I’m trapped in the ivory tower, forever young.<br>
If heaven and earth offer no refuge,<br>
let poetry debts buy wine.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lone Zither<br>
October 6, 2024<br>
Yongle Palace, Guangren King Temple, Stork Tower, Guan Yu Temple, Yuncheng</strong></p>
<p>A rushed group tour in Yuncheng left little time for details. At Stork Tower, I spotted a stall boldly labeled &ldquo;Selling Original Poetry.&rdquo; After touring the new tower, I revisited the collection, struck by lingering awe. Wei Taoran, inspired by a Dali poetess, returned to literature—I too once wrote many poems, mostly idle scribbles, never considering it a livelihood.<br>
In high school, I gifted my poetry drafts to someone. After the breakup, I scarcely wrote again. First, gaming consumed me—I read little, my pen dry, my efforts unsatisfying. Second, life blurred like fog—neither piercing nor clear, I drifted in haze. Third, the ivory tower’s monotony left me numb, devoid of poetic spark.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/3184801327.jpg" alt="IMG_2131 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/1585398490.jpg" alt="IMG_2134 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/3750612929.jpg" alt="IMG_2158 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/3048377807.jpg" alt="IMG_2214 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/1157009.jpg" alt="IMG_2233 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/343590413.jpg" alt="IMG_2234 (1).JPG"><br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/915481746.jpg" alt="IMG_2235 (1).JPG"></p>
<h2 id="afterword">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#afterword"></a>
Afterword
</h2><p>The three cities of southern Shanxi each have their charm.<br>
Jincheng is bustling, with efficient buses and dedicated routes to attractions. Arriving downtown, the streets blaze with light.<br>
Linfen is peculiar—even areas around the bus station are dark, and distant sites lack dedicated transit, making private hires costly. Its public toilets are uniquely varied—I biked past twenty-plus on shared e-scooters, no two alike.<br>
Yuncheng thrives—shops and stalls pack main roads and alleys, with rumors of north-south markets (and delicious, honest-to-goodness buns).</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/10/3704126306.jpg" alt="IMG_2091.JPG"></p>
        <hr><p>本文 2024-10-08 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2024-10-08</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Poetry</category>
      
    </item>
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaning on railings, I hear the rain rushing; For my homeland my heart is aching.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/thoughts/%E5%87%AD%E6%A0%8F%E9%9D%99%E5%90%AC%E6%BD%87%E6%BD%87%E9%9B%A8%E6%95%85%E5%9B%BD%E4%BA%BA%E6%B0%91%E6%9C%89%E6%89%80%E6%80%9D/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 17:54:04 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/thoughts/%E5%87%AD%E6%A0%8F%E9%9D%99%E5%90%AC%E6%BD%87%E6%BD%87%E9%9B%A8%E6%95%85%E5%9B%BD%E4%BA%BA%E6%B0%91%E6%9C%89%E6%89%80%E6%80%9D/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>Leaning on railings, I hear the rain rushing; For my homeland my heart is aching.</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <p>&ldquo;I have a dream that one day, the brilliant sunlight will pierce through the dark forest.&rdquo;</p>
<p>But here, the sun was setting, now only revealing the tip of its crown above the distant mountains, like a dazzling gem embedded in the peaks. The child had already run far ahead, bathed together with the grassland in the golden hues of twilight.</p>
<p>The sun is about to set, and your child isn’t afraid?</p>
<p>&ldquo;Of course not. She knows the sun will rise again tomorrow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Good night.<br>
<img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2024/09/2683784600.jpg" alt="Mao1.JPG"></p>
        <hr><p>本文 2024-09-09 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2024-09-09</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Thoughts</category>
      
    </item>
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems Written in High School</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E9%AB%98%E4%B8%AD%E5%86%99%E7%9A%84%E8%AF%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 11:20:23 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E9%AB%98%E4%B8%AD%E5%86%99%E7%9A%84%E8%AF%97/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poems Written in High School</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <h2 id="self-statement">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#self-statement"></a>
Self-Statement
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/3082710100.jpeg" alt="Self-Statement"></p>
<h2 id="memories-of-west-lake-after-the-rain">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#memories-of-west-lake-after-the-rain"></a>
Memories of West Lake After the Rain
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/1156284995.jpeg" alt="Memories of West Lake After the Rain"></p>
<h2 id="heaven-and-earth-in-a-cup">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#heaven-and-earth-in-a-cup"></a>
Heaven and Earth in a Cup
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/1548716889.jpeg" alt="Heaven and Earth in a Cup"></p>
<h2 id="casual-notes-part-1">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#casual-notes-part-1"></a>
Casual Notes (Part 1)
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/4021042374.jpeg" alt="Casual Notes (Part 1)"></p>
<h2 id="treading-on-grass">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#treading-on-grass"></a>
Treading on Grass
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/132648365.jpeg" alt="Treading on Grass"></p>
<h2 id="fishing-for-the-moon">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#fishing-for-the-moon"></a>
Fishing for the Moon
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/1357694788.jpeg" alt="Fishing for the Moon"></p>
<h2 id="variation-prelude-to-water-melody--remembering-an-old-friend">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#variation-prelude-to-water-melody--remembering-an-old-friend"></a>
[Variation] Prelude to Water Melody • Remembering an Old Friend
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/1736298854.jpeg" alt="Variation Prelude to Water Melody • Remembering an Old Friend"></p>
<h2 id="may-i-be-the-star-and-you-the-moon">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#may-i-be-the-star-and-you-the-moon"></a>
May I Be the Star and You the Moon
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/3607825259.jpeg" alt="May I Be the Star and You the Moon"></p>
<h2 id="playful-dedication-to-jiarui">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#playful-dedication-to-jiarui"></a>
Playful Dedication to Jiarui
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/3971791820.jpeg" alt="Playful Dedication to Jiarui"></p>
        <hr><p>本文 2023-11-22 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2023-11-22</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Poetry</category>
      
    </item>
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recently Written Poems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E6%9C%80%E8%BF%91%E5%86%99%E7%9A%84%E8%AF%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:00:41 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E6%9C%80%E8%BF%91%E5%86%99%E7%9A%84%E8%AF%97/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>Recently Written Poems</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <h2 id="inseparable">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#inseparable"></a>
Inseparable
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/586131506.jpg" alt="Inseparable"></p>
<h2 id="winter">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#winter"></a>
Winter
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/2722051457.jpg" alt="Winter"></p>
<h2 id="topic-the-world-will-end-in-10-minutes-what-would-you-do">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#topic-the-world-will-end-in-10-minutes-what-would-you-do"></a>
Topic: The world will end in 10 minutes. What would you do?
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/950597167.jpg" alt="Topic: The world will end in 10 minutes. What would you do?"></p>
<h2 id="the-human-heart-is-on-the-left-side-so-how-can-an-embrace-make-hearts-align">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#the-human-heart-is-on-the-left-side-so-how-can-an-embrace-make-hearts-align"></a>
The human heart is on the left side, so how can an embrace make hearts align?
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/3662692789.jpg" alt="The human heart is on the left side, so how can an embrace make hearts align?"></p>
<h2 id="poet-torch-traveler">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#poet-torch-traveler"></a>
Poet, Torch, Traveler
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/3007367405.jpeg" alt="Poet, Torch, Traveler"></p>
<h2 id="the-sun-is-out">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#the-sun-is-out"></a>
The Sun Is Out
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/2167400162.jpeg" alt="The Sun Is Out"></p>
<h2 id="a-three-line-love-poem-for-you">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#a-three-line-love-poem-for-you"></a>
A Three-Line Love Poem for You
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/2769280253.jpeg" alt="A Three-Line Love Poem for You"></p>
<h2 id="leaning-on-the-railing-i-ask">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#leaning-on-the-railing-i-ask"></a>
Leaning on the Railing, I Ask
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/2281894345.jpg" alt="Leaning on the Railing, I Ask"></p>
<h2 id="a-normal-day">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#a-normal-day"></a>
A Normal Day
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/612754544.jpg" alt="A Normal Day"></p>
<h2 id="little-joys">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#little-joys"></a>
Little Joys
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/4288629955.jpg" alt="Little Joys"></p>
<h2 id="travel-notes">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#travel-notes"></a>
Travel Notes
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/3004464166.jpg" alt="Travel Notes"></p>
<h2 id="red-carpet">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#red-carpet"></a>
Red Carpet
</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/3569376525.jpg" alt="Red Carpet"></p>
        <hr><p>本文 2023-11-18 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2023-11-18</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Poetry</category>
      
    </item>
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems written during the 2023 Spring Festival</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/2023%E5%B9%B4%E6%98%A5%E8%8A%82%E6%9C%9F%E9%97%B4%E5%86%99%E7%9A%84%E8%AF%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 20:26:53 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/2023%E5%B9%B4%E6%98%A5%E8%8A%82%E6%9C%9F%E9%97%B4%E5%86%99%E7%9A%84%E8%AF%97/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>Poems written during the 2023 Spring Festival</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/2526097091.jpg" alt="1"></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/GuZhengSVT/Hugo-media/2023/11/1050186067.jpg" alt="2"></p>

        <hr><p>本文 2023-01-28 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2023-01-28</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Poetry</category>
      
    </item>
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond a thousand barren hills, the trees stand bare.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E8%90%BD%E6%9C%A8%E5%8D%83%E5%B1%B1%E5%A4%96/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 17:26:44 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E8%90%BD%E6%9C%A8%E5%8D%83%E5%B1%B1%E5%A4%96/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>Beyond a thousand barren hills, the trees stand bare.</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Bare hills reveal the sky&rsquo;s vast dome;<br>
Moonlit river flows in clarity.&rdquo;<br>
— Huang Tingjian, <em>Ascending the Happy Tower</em></p></blockquote>
<p>I lost the match, clutching my aching hand,<br>
trudging alone along the roadside.</p>
<p>Autumn dusk yellows autumn leaves,<br>
autumn wind scatters autumn longing.</p>
<p>Pale ginkgo leaves fall like fine rain,<br>
brown sycamore leaves spill between the lines.</p>
<p>This apricot-hued snow blurs my vision—<br>
momentarily indistinguishable:<br>
which are sycamore&rsquo;s crimson descent,<br>
which are ginkgo&rsquo;s drifting vermilion,<br>
still adorned with youths&rsquo; bustle<br>
and lovers&rsquo; tears.</p>
<p>Let northern fallen timber bury<br>
the solitude of homeward wanderers.</p>
<p>O southern wind,<br>
might you grant us<br>
the same southern snowfall?</p>
<p>September 28, 2022<br>
Xi&rsquo;an</p>

        <hr><p>本文 2022-09-28 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2022-09-28</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Poetry</category>
      
    </item>
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Short Poems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E7%9F%AD%E8%AF%97%E7%B2%BE%E9%80%89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 22:20:41 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E7%9F%AD%E8%AF%97%E7%B2%BE%E9%80%89/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>Selected Short Poems</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <p>You stand on the bridge to gaze at the view,<br>
While someone watches you from a tower.<br>
The bright moon adorns your window,<br>
And you adorn another’s dream.</p>
<p>— <em>Fragment</em> by Bian Zhilin</p>
<p>How I wish for a doorway,<br>
Where morning sunlight falls on the grass.<br>
We stand there, leaning against the door,<br>
Low as it is, the sun shines bright.<br>
The grass sows its seeds, the wind shakes the leaves,<br>
We stand, silent, and it is enough.</p>
<p>— Gu Cheng, <em>A Generation</em>, <em>Avoidance</em>, <em>Before the Door</em></p>
<p>Spring sorrow waits for wine to drown,<br>
Boats rock on the river, curtains beckon from towers.<br>
Time slips away too soon—<br>
Cherries redden, bananas green.</p>
<p>— <em>A Twig of Mume Blossoms</em> by Jiang Jie</p>
<p>From now on, I care not for fine nights,<br>
Let the bright moon sink west without me.</p>
<p>— <em>Writing Emotion</em> by Li Yi</p>
<p>The hills have trees, and trees have branches,<br>
My heart adores you, but you do not know.</p>
<p>— <em>Song of the Yue Boatman</em>, Anonymous</p>
<p>The carved die inlaid with red beans—<br>
Deep in my bones, do you know this longing?</p>
<p>— <em>New Lyrics to Willow Branches</em> by Wen Tingyun</p>
<p>A crane’s shadow crosses the cold pond,<br>
The frigid moon buries the flower’s soul.</p>
<p>— <em>Dream of the Red Chamber</em></p>
<p>Though knowing this love brings no good,<br>
I can’t help but ache with tender madness.</p>
<p>— Li Shangyin</p>
<p>What the world holds least firm—<br>
Youth fades like flowers from the mirror, from the tree.</p>
<p>— <em>Butterfly in Love with Flowers</em> by Wang Guowei</p>
<p>Not a flower, not a mist,<br>
Coming at midnight, gone by dawn,<br>
Like a spring dream—how long does it stay?<br>
Like morning clouds—where does it drift?</p>
<p>— <em>Not a Flower</em> by Bai Juyi</p>
<p>Helpless before morning’s chill rain, evening’s wind—<br>
Life’s long regrets flow east like endless rivers.</p>
<p>— Li Yu’s poetry</p>
<p>Drunk, I forget the sky mirrors the water,<br>
A boatful of clear dreams presses down the Milky Way.</p>
<p>— <em>Inscription on Longyang’s Green Grass Lake</em> by Tang Wenru</p>
<p>Free petals drift light as dreams,<br>
Endless drizzle fine as sorrow.</p>
<p>— <em>Silk-Washing Stream</em> by Qin Guan</p>
<p>In youth, I listened to rain in song-filled towers,<br>
Red candles dim behind silk curtains.<br>
In middle age, I listened to rain on a traveler’s boat,<br>
Wide river, low clouds, lone goose crying in west wind.<br>
Now I listen to rain beneath a temple’s eaves,<br>
My hair already streaked with stars.<br>
Joys and sorrows, partings and reunions—all unfeeling.<br>
Let the raindrops on the steps fall till dawn.</p>
<p>— <em>Listening to the Rain</em> by Jiang Jie</p>
<p>The moon sets, crows cry, frost fills the sky,<br>
River maples, fishing fires—sleeping in sorrow.</p>
<p>— <em>Mooring by Maple Bridge at Night</em> by Zhang Ji</p>
<p>That gentlest bow of your head,<br>
Like a lotus flower shy of the cool breeze.</p>
<p>— <em>By Chance</em>, <em>Sayonara</em> by Xu Zhimo</p>
<p>If there is an afterlife, I’d be a tree,<br>
Standing eternal, without joy or sorrow.<br>
Half rooted in earth, serene,<br>
Half dancing in the wind;<br>
Half offering shade,<br>
Half basking in sunlight.<br>
Silent, proud,<br>
Never leaning, never seeking.</p>
<p>— <em>If There Is an Afterlife</em> by Sanmao</p>
<p>So I open the yellowed title page,<br>
Fate bound it clumsily.<br>
Tearfully, I read it again and again,<br>
Yet must admit—<br>
Youth is a book too hastily written.</p>
<p>— <em>Youth</em> by Xi Murong</p>
<p>Let life be beautiful like summer flowers,<br>
And death like autumn leaves.</p>
<p>The world has kissed my soul with its pain,<br>
Asking for its return in songs.</p>
<p>Only through the grind of hell<br>
Can one forge the power to create heaven;<br>
Only fingers bleeding from the strings<br>
Can play the world’s most haunting music.</p>
<p>When you weep for missing the sun,<br>
You also miss the stars.</p>
<p>The sky leaves no trace of wings,<br>
But I have flown.</p>
<p>My eyes rain for her,<br>
But my heart holds an umbrella—<br>
This is love.</p>
<p>— <em>Stray Birds</em>, <em>Gitanjali</em> by Rabindranath Tagore</p>
<p>White sun, scattered clouds—startled apart,<br>
Beneath the flowers, no one speaks of idleness.</p>
<p>— <em>Floating Life</em> by Gu Zhe</p>
<p>Ten miles of flat lake, frost-filled sky,<br>
Each inch of dark hair grieves fleeting youth.<br>
Gazing alone at the moon, longing for care,<br>
I envy not immortals, but lovebirds paired.</p>
<p>— From the film <em>A Chinese Ghost Story</em></p>
<p>Morning breezes will still brush my face,<br>
Cuckoos will still sing on branches,<br>
Earth will still breathe its fragrance,<br>
Red maples will still flutter and fade.<br>
I choose to believe, as ever,<br>
That amid life’s cold ashes,<br>
Remembering all about you<br>
Was always my lifelong sorrow.</p>
<p>— Zhang Hansi, <em>Abnormal Human Syndromes</em> (Léont Blanc)</p>
<p>Octopus pot—<br>
A fleeting dream<br>
Under the summer moon.</p>
<p>— Matsuo Bashō</p>
<p>Flower shadows sway—<br>
I long to tread them,<br>
Moonlit crags ahead.</p>
<p>— Hara Sekitei</p>
<p>Grass in haze,<br>
Water soundless—<br>
Dusk falls.</p>
<p>— Yosa Buson</p>
<p>A lone horse, dust-stained,<br>
A thousand peaks at dawn and dusk.<br>
Gazing far where the sunset fades,<br>
I linger toward distant hills.<br>
Old post-station flowers by the road,<br>
A wild village, bamboo fences aglow.<br>
Who pities my backward glance,<br>
Step by step, longing for southern boughs?</p>
<p>— <em>Staying Late at Bamboo Lodge, Remembering Past Travels in Ganyue</em> by Liu Changqing (Tang Dynasty)</p>

        <hr><p>本文 2022-09-16 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2022-09-16</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Poetry</category>
      
    </item>
    
    
      
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Selected Poems from *Dream of the Red Chamber*</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E7%BA%A2%E6%A5%BC%E6%A2%A6%E8%AF%97%E8%AF%8D%E7%B2%BE%E9%80%89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 17:29:44 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>lvbowen040427@163.com (孤筝)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/post/poetry/%E7%BA%A2%E6%A5%BC%E6%A2%A6%E8%AF%97%E8%AF%8D%E7%B2%BE%E9%80%89/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<h1>Selected Poems from *Dream of the Red Chamber*</h1><p>作者: 孤筝 (lvbowen040427@163.com)</p>
          <p><strong>Prelude</strong></p>
<p>In realms primordial who played the lover?<br>
None but the breeze and moon enchanted me.<br>
So now I seize these days of dark spring weather<br>
To ease my heart by writing this poor story.<br>
Hence this <em>Dream of Golden Days</em>,<br>
This lament for my golden girls.</p>
<p><strong>[Life&rsquo;s Mistakes]</strong></p>
<p>They keep saying this golden match is blest,<br>
Yet I recall the pledge between plant and stone.<br>
Vainly I face this snow of classic purity,<br>
Still can&rsquo;t forget that fairy wood forlorn.<br>
Now I know the fairest bloom is the most fragile,<br>
And trust no more the love that&rsquo;s pledged in vain.<br>
Though we seem paired as phoenixes in life,<br>
My heart to the end remains unfulfilled.<br>
<em>(Daiyu, Baochai)</em></p>
<p><strong>[Vain Longing]</strong></p>
<p>One is a flower from paradise,<br>
One a pure jade without spot or stain.<br>
If one is not fated to be his bride,<br>
Why did she meet him again in this life?<br>
If one is fated to be his bride,<br>
Why does her love come to nothing in the end?<br>
One sighs to no purpose,<br>
The other yearns in vain;<br>
One is the moon reflected in the water,<br>
The other but a flower in the mirror.<br>
How many tears can well from her eyes?<br>
Can they flow on from autumn till winter,<br>
From spring till summer?<br>
<em>(Daiyu, Baoyu)</em></p>
<p><strong>[Death&rsquo;s Uncertainty]</strong></p>
<p>In the full bloom of fortune,<br>
Death comes unexpected.<br>
With staring eyes,<br>
She abandons all worldly affairs.<br>
Drifting, drifting,<br>
Her fragrant soul is spent.<br>
Gazing toward home,<br>
Mountains and rivers bar the way.<br>
In dreams she tells her parents:<br>
&ldquo;Your child has gone to the Yellow Spring.<br>
O kinsmen,<br>
Retreat before it is too late!&rdquo;<br>
<em>(Yuanchun)</em></p>
<p><strong>[Separation of Flesh and Bone]</strong></p>
<p>Three thousand li the wind and waves have blown<br>
Me far from home and all my kin.<br>
Lest grief should wear my parents out,<br>
I beg them not to mourn for me.<br>
Since poverty and riches are decreed,<br>
Partings and reunions are fated too.<br>
Though from today we dwell apart,<br>
Be comforted and live at peace.<br>
I must go now —<br>
Do not grieve for me!<br>
<em>(Tanchun)</em></p>
<p><strong>[False Love]</strong></p>
<p>A wolf in the hills, a savage beast,<br>
He thinks nothing of past obligations.<br>
Proud, lewd and cruel, he schemes for his base lusts.<br>
He looks on a gentle beauty as a willow,<br>
Tramples a noble family&rsquo;s daughter in the mud.<br>
Alas, her sweet soul in a year has fled.<br>
<em>(Yingchun)</em></p>
<p><strong>[Hard to Escape the World]</strong></p>
<p>Her beauty is rare as an orchid,<br>
Her talents supreme as an immortal.<br>
Heaven made her eccentric,<br>
Too proud to take meat as food,<br>
Disdaining silk and satin.<br>
But the higher the rank, the greater the envy;<br>
The purer her chastity, the sharper the spite.<br>
Alas, in dim-lit halls she will grow old,<br>
Missing the splendour of crimson towers,<br>
Till she falls at last into the mire.<br>
Pure white jade sunk in the filth —<br>
No need for lords to sigh at her fate.<br>
<em>(Miaoyu)</em></p>
<p><strong>[Grief in the Midst of Joy]</strong></p>
<p>While still in swaddling clothes<br>
She lost her parents,<br>
And though born to silken luxury<br>
No one spoiled her.<br>
Happy her nature, open-hearted and generous,<br>
Never a slave to love&rsquo;s foolish passion,<br>
She shone like moonlight on jade halls.<br>
She was wed to a talented, handsome husband,<br>
Hoping for long life together<br>
To make up for her wretched childhood.<br>
Yet soon the clouds scatter over Chu Gorge,<br>
The river dries up in the land of streams.<br>
This is the common fate of mortals —<br>
Why vainly grieve?<br>
<em>(Xiangyun)</em></p>
<p><strong>[The Vanity of Spring]</strong></p>
<p>She sees through the three springs,<br>
What use are peach and plum?<br>
She quenches the fire of youth<br>
To seek pure calm.<br>
What though the heavenly peach blooms fair,<br>
The clouds are thick with almond flowers?<br>
In the end, who can escape autumn?<br>
See there,<br>
In the village of white poplars<br>
People weep,<br>
And ghosts chant under green maples.<br>
Grave mounds are lost in rank weeds.<br>
The rich of yesterday are poor today,<br>
Spring&rsquo;s flowers wither in fall.<br>
Who can escape the doom of birth and death?<br>
They say<br>
In the Western Paradise<br>
The sacred trees bear fruit of immortality.<br>
<em>(Xichun)</em></p>
<p><strong>[Too Much Cunning]</strong></p>
<p>Too much cunning in plotting and scheming,<br>
Too much cunning brings your life to nothing.<br>
Your heart is broken in life,<br>
Your ghost in death must wander.<br>
A rich house, a peaceful home —<br>
In the end all is scattered.<br>
Vain your anxious planning for half a lifetime,<br>
Like a fitful dream at dead of night.<br>
Suddenly the great mansion totters,<br>
The lamp flickers in the wind.<br>
Ah! Joy turns to sorrow,<br>
Human life is hard to predict.<br>
<em>(Xifeng)</em></p>
<p><strong>[Leftover Blessings]</strong></p>
<p>Leftover blessings, leftover blessings,<br>
Unexpectedly she meets a saviour.<br>
Lucky her mother, lucky her mother,<br>
Who stored up virtue.<br>
Exhort all men to succour the poor and needy,<br>
Not like that heartless uncle and cousin who loved silver<br>
And forgot their own flesh and blood!<br>
For fate has its reckonings,<br>
And Heaven its way.<br>
<em>(Qiaojie)</em></p>
<p><strong>[The End of Good Fortune]</strong></p>
<p>Fragrant dust falls when painted beams crumble.<br>
Seductive charms and beauty<br>
Brought the house to ruin.<br>
The fault began with Jing,<br>
The guilt lies first with Ning —<br>
But all sins spring from lust.<br>
<em>(Qin Keqing)</em></p>
<p><strong>[Late Glory]</strong></p>
<p>Love in the mirror gone,<br>
How can fame in dreams endure?<br>
Her glorious youth sped fast!<br>
No more the nuptial bed.<br>
Her pearl crown and phoenix cape<br>
Cannot avert the doom of death.<br>
Proudly she wears her hairpin of office,<br>
Proudly she wears her hairpin of office;<br>
Brightly her golden badge of honour,<br>
Splendid her noble rank,<br>
Splendid her noble rank —<br>
But dark the road to the Yellow Spring.<br>
Ask of ancient generals and ministers —<br>
Are any left?<br>
Only an empty name for men to praise.<br>
<em>(Li Wan)</em></p>
<p><strong>[Epilogue: Each Bird Flies Back to Its Wood]</strong></p>
<p>The office-holder&rsquo;s wealth is all spent. <em>(Xiangyun)</em><br>
The rich man&rsquo;s family is completely ruined. <em>(Baochai)</em><br>
The kind escape with their lives. <em>(Qiaojie)</em><br>
The cruel meet with retribution. <em>(Miaoyu)</em><br>
Those who took a life have paid with their own. <em>(Yingchun)</em><br>
The tears one owed have all been shed. <em>(Daiyu)</em><br>
Not light the retribution for sins. <em>(Qin Keqing)</em><br>
Partings and reunions are predestined. <em>(Tanchun)</em><br>
To know your fate, ask about your past life. <em>(Yuanchun)</em><br>
Luck comes with old age. <em>(Li Wan)</em><br>
The disillusioned escape from the world. <em>(Xichun)</em><br>
The infatuated throw away their lives. <em>(Xifeng)</em><br>
Like birds who, having eaten, fly back to the wood,<br>
Leaving the landscape white and desolate.</p>
<p><strong>Author&rsquo;s Origin</strong></p>
<p>At the point of saddest passion,<br>
The absurd seems most pitiful.<br>
All men share the same dream,<br>
Laugh not at the world&rsquo;s folly!</p>
<p><strong>Author&rsquo;s Inscription</strong></p>
<p>Pages full of idle words,<br>
Penned with hot and bitter tears.<br>
All men call the author mad,<br>
None his secret message hears.</p>
<p><strong>Commentary on the &ldquo;Song of Good Fortune&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Mean huts and empty halls<br>
Where once were beds of state;<br>
Dry grass and withered weeds<br>
Where once were flowers in bloom.<br>
Cobwebs hang from carved rafters,<br>
While gauze now covers the window.<br>
What though rouge and powder were fresh,<br>
Now white locks hang at the temples?<br>
Yesterday yellow earth received white bones,<br>
Today red lanterns light the love-birds&rsquo; nest.<br>
Gold fills the chests, silver the boxes,<br>
But soon all turn to beggars, scoffed at by all.<br>
While mourning others&rsquo; untimely death,<br>
You may die yourself unawares.<br>
Though you give your son good training,<br>
He may turn out a brigand.<br>
Choosing a fine husband for your daughter,<br>
She may end as a singsong girl.<br>
Too low a rank invites disgrace,<br>
Too much wealth may bring ruin.<br>
Yesterday in rags you shivered with cold,<br>
Today in purple robes you fret at the confinement.<br>
All is confusion as one act ends, another starts;<br>
Mistaking the transient for the eternal,<br>
How absurd in the end<br>
To slave for others!</p>
<p><strong>Linjiangxian - Baochai</strong></p>
<p>Before white marble halls<br>
Spring dances in the breeze,<br>
Evenly wafted by the east wind.<br>
Bees and butterflies flit in swarms —<br>
Why drift away with the stream?<br>
Why sink in the dust?<br>
Thousands of strands remain unchanged,<br>
Let them join or part as they will.<br>
Laugh not at these flowers rootless,<br>
But borrow their power to soar on high!</p>
<p><strong>Xijiangyue - Baoqin</strong></p>
<p>The Han garden&rsquo;s blooms are few,<br>
The Sui Dyke&rsquo;s willows endless.<br>
Spring&rsquo;s work is left to the east wind,<br>
Moonlight and mume-blossoms a dream.<br>
In how many courtyards petals lie scattered?<br>
Whose gauze curtains breathe fragrance?<br>
North and south of the river it is the same —<br>
Only the parting grieves.</p>
<p><strong>Mid-Autumn Festival Couplets</strong></p>
<p>On mid-autumn&rsquo;s festive night<br>
We roam as at the Feast of Lanterns.<br>
The sky is strewn with stars,<br>
The earth with music loud.<br>
In many homes goblets fly,<br>
No doors are closed.<br>
The light wind blows chilly,<br>
The fine night is merry.<br>
Old men mock at cake-fighters,<br>
Young girls laugh at melon-carvers.<br>
Fragrant cassia blooms,<br>
Golden day-lilies flourish.<br>
Candles light the feast,<br>
Wine-cups crowd the garden.<br>
Teams are formed for forfeits,<br>
Guessing games played.<br>
Dice throw crimson spots,<br>
Drums pass flowers fast.<br>
Clear light fills the courtyard,<br>
Silver bathes the world.<br>
No guests outrank hosts,<br>
Poems are judged by all.<br>
Some muse by the balustrade,<br>
Some watch from the door.<br>
Though wine is finished,<br>
The fun is not over.<br>
As talk and laughter fade,<br>
Frost leaves its traces.<br>
Dew beads morning mushrooms,<br>
Mist veils evening trees.<br>
Swift autumn streams gush,<br>
Wind-blown leaves gather.<br>
The Weaving Maid shines pure,<br>
The Silver Toad breathes deep.<br>
The hare in the moon pounds herbs,<br>
Men race to the Palace of the Moon.<br>
They pass the stars in the Dipper,<br>
Ride a raft to the Celestial River.<br>
The full moon may wane,<br>
The bright orb may dim.<br>
The water-clock drips dry,<br>
The lamp by the window gutters.<br>
A stork&rsquo;s shadow crosses cold pool,<br>
Cold moon buries flowers&rsquo; souls.<br>
Incense from the golden tripod spent,<br>
Ice chills the jade bowl.<br>
The flute makes the widow weep,<br>
The quilt warms the maid.<br>
The phoenix curtain hangs idle,<br>
The peacock screen folded.<br>
Dew thick, moss grows slippery,<br>
Frost heavy, bamboos hard to grasp.<br>
Still we skirt winding pools,<br>
Climb the silent hill.<br>
Strange rocks crouch like monsters,<br>
Gnarled trees crouch like tigers.<br>
The tortoise glows in morning light,<br>
The screen glistens with dew.<br>
Birds in thousands of trees call,<br>
Apes in the valley shriek.<br>
Familiar with the path, we forget its turns,<br>
Knowing the source, we need not ask.<br>
Bells chime from Green Lattice Nunnery,<br>
Cocks crow in Paddy-Sweet Cottage.<br>
Joy may lead to sorrow,<br>
Freedom from care to vexation.<br>
Sweet fancies must be indulged alone,<br>
To whom tell our refined delight?<br>
All night we talk,<br>
Brew tea and analyze.</p>

        <hr><p>本文 2022-09-09 首发于 <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>孤筝の温暖小家</a>，最后修改于 2022-09-09</p><p>All website licensed under CC BY 4.0</p>]]>
      </description>
        <category>Poetry</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
